A Guide to the Guy Davenport Papers 1956-1983
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Letters 1956-1883
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to "Lorenzo caro" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions ads for Archilochos, doing a review for Louise Bogan's translation of Goethe's Elective Affinities] 1964 February 9, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions the release of Archilochos, Hugh Kenner's visit with Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, and Stan Brakhage's visit to Lexington] 1964 March 22, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [asking about sending a copy of Archilochos to Marianne Moore and to Scott] April 9, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses his summer trip to Europe which included a stay with Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, and mentions Hugo Dyson and Marianne Moore's new poem] 1964 September 5, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions illness of Mary Jo Kenner, his work in reviews and books, and receipt of Warren Krupsaw portrait of Marianne Moore] 1964 September 13, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, Donald Hall, Hugh Kenner, and Bill Arrowsmith] 1964 September 28, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re Mary Jo Kenner's death the previous day] 1964 December 10, TPCS
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions the death of Mary Jo Kenner, his friend Steve's visit to John Burroughs, Jack Smith, and Allen Ginsberg] 1964 December 20, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions his book on Sappho] 1964 December 28, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [re his quiet holiday, mentions movies of Hugh Kenner showing Ezra Pound, Olga Rudge, and Mary Jo Kenner] 1964 December 30, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [sending the address of Louis Zukofsky, mentions Hugh Kenner and Stan Brakhage] 1965 February 2, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [briefly discusses Stan Brakhage and his movie Dog Star Man] 1965 February 23, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [relays Hugh Kenner's news from Europe about Ezra Pound, Olga Rudge, and Dorothy Pound, and mentions his friend Steve's association with Andy Warhol and Bobby Rauschenberg] 1965 March 20, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, [Lexington], to Laurence Scott, [Cambridge], [mentions Marianne Moore, Peggy Bacon, Robert Payne, and the Pound triangle] 1965 April 6, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to "Carissimo Laurenzaccio" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, Hugh Kenner, Gordon Adams, and the possible development of a new literary department at the University of Kentucky] 1965 April 16, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re lack of communication from Olga Rudge, and mentions Jonas Mekas, Jonathan Williams, Rafe Eugene Meatyard, and Elf Stephanos] 1965 April 13, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Ezra and Dorothy Pound, Henry James lecturing at Bryn Mawr, Marianne Moore, and Thomas Stearns Eliot] 1965 April 19, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to "Il mio Laurenzaccio carissimo" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [writes that he is pleased with Marianne Moore's appraisal of his Tolkien essay, and mentions "film-pop-art people"] 1965 April 21, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re a broadside sent by Scott and Toni Seymour's Bronze of his friend Steve] 1965, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [praises The Talisman, requests permission to publish from Dorothy Pound, and mentions Christopher Middleton, Stan Brakhage, Carl Andre, P. Adams Sitney, Hugh Kenner, J.R.R. Tolkien, and Robert Kelly] 1965 June 22, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [briefly discusses a visit to the University of Kentucky by Eudora Welty] 1965 September 26, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [re visitors, Louis and Celia Zukofsky] 1965 October 7, TPCS
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions Hugh Kenner, Stan Brakhage, and Ezra Pound] 1965 October 29, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions Jonathan Williams, Leroi Jones, and new friend Bonnie Jean] 1965 December 6, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [indicating that his translation of Gabriele D'Annunzio will be a shock and writing that he has been reading about him] 1966 January 13, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [comments on the Lowell broadside and plans to get cooperation from Ezra Pound concerning "Canto CX"] 1966 January 21, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions Walter Hooper (C.S. Lewis' secretary) and Louis and Celia Zukofsky, and writes that he has finished a handbook on The Odyssey and that he is nearing completion on his Flowers & Leaves] 1966 March 8, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions Louis Zukofsky, writes that he is finishing a long essay on Ezra Pound for Eva Hesse and that he is being asked to do an Iliad companion volume to his Odyssey] 1966 [May 31], TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses works in progress, including Iliad and Odyssey handbooks, translations of Helen and Dyskolos, and Ezra Pound's Conversations and the Cantos, and preparations for his autumn classes] 1966 July 22, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions distinguished visitors Jonathan Williams and Ronald Johnson, Edward Field, Peter Kubelka, Charles Stein, and Jonathan Greene] 1966 September 2, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses briefly news of Ezra Pound and his own life with Bonnie Jean] 1966 October 7, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [thanks him for the copy of W[ystan] H[ugh] Auden's handsome book, and mentions working on his Dyskolos] 1966 October 14, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, [Lexington], to Laurence Scott, [Cambridge], [thanks him for the [Richard] Ellman essay on Ezra Pound and W[illiam] B[utler] Y[eats], and comments that he has too much work to do] 1966 November 18, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to "Caro Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Boston, [mentions Sir Mawdis Bowra, that his Aunt Mae passed away from complications following an accident, that he is trying to catch up on deadlines, and that he heard John Jacob Niles in concert] 1966 December 1, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [expecting information on Ezra Pound, and mentions the ineptness in the literary field and Gordon Cairnie's news of Marianne Moore attending the Truman Capote dance, with enclosures of Japanese drawings] 1967 January 9, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Boston, [mentions his visit to Thomas Merton, finishing his "Resurrection in Cookham Churchyard," and running the Southern Literary Festival] 1967 March 15, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [comments on Marianne Moore's illness, moving to a house surrounded by "Blue Grass dignitaries," and mentions visitors Harry Levin, Eudora Welty, Bucky Fuller, Thomas Merton, and William F. Buckley, Jr., and relates that he is writing a novel about Tatlin] 1970 October 17, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [comments that he has just "finished the fourth Ezra Pound table," describes the decor of his living room, and mentions his first fiction, "Aeroplanes at Brescia"] 1970 December 7, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, [Ann Arbor], [acknowledges Marianne Moore's death, discusses Ezra Pound, Dorothy Pound, and Olga Rudge, and mentions Hugh Kenner's book The Pound Era] 1972 February 13, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [writes that he is still doing "prose, poetry, drawing," describes his and Bonnie Jean's trips to France, mentions that his Tatlin! has received many reviews, and shares a Pound anecdote] 1974 December 19, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions John Shannon, Louis Zukofsky, and Eudora Welty] 1977 April 11, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions Donald Hall, Eudora Welty, and finishing some books and stories] 1979 November 9, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions his archives at various institutions, discusses his six books in the press, and relates that he is now "the occupant of a Chair" and is only teaching one course a semester] 1983 August 4, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [asks if he has heard from Ezra Pound, mentions Marianne Moore, and indicates that he wants to receive erotica through the mail] June 27, AL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [mentions the beginning summer school] June 28, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [discusses several books by Wilkie Collins] n.d., TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - "Andre Marcueil" [Guy Davenport], to "Caro Lauro" [Laurence Scott], [re 26 Fructidor, translating more ancient poets after having done Archilochos, and discusses the literary work of Paul [ ]] n.d., ALS, 1 p.
  - "Cousin Vergil Lee" [Guy Davenport], Anderson, to Laurence Scott, [re family news] n.d., APCS
  - Guy Davenport, [Anderson], to Laurence Scott, [writes about a day of archeological exploration with his family in Elbert County, Georgia] n.d., ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [writing literary trivia] n.d., TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [sends biographical information on Jonathan Williams] n.d., TL, 1 p.
- Series III: Drawings by Guy Davenport
  - "William Blake at Felpham" 1959
  - "E.P., Litt. D. Oxon...giving his doctoral address" 1960
  - "Monckton Milnes [Lord Houghton] & the Author of 'Shirley'" n.d.
  - "The Queen's Watercolour Lesson" with "The Queen's Post-Prandial" on the verso n.d.
  - Untitled, [The Queen's Watercolour Lesson?], "11 April 1910"
  - "Mrs. Anne Radcliffe in a Tiepolo landscape" n.d.
  - "Peaches at Laurence Scott's!" n.d.
  - Samurai Warrior n.d.
  - "A.C. Swinburne" n.d.